The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
♪ Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano ♪
The dreams I see are my secret
♪ Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano ♪
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
♪ Akai manto hira hira ♪
A red cape fluttering
♪ Uma o tobasu oujo ♪
Galloping on a horse—the princess
♪ Sore ga atashi ♪
That’s me!
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Ribon no kishi wa ♪
The Knight of the Ribbon,
♪ Honto wa hontto wa ♪
Truly, truly,
♪ Atashi nano sa ♪
It’s really me!
Twenty-Second Episode
A New King
The Coronation
If I put my mind to it, I can do it too.
Until now, I've been weak and cowardly.
Alright, I have courage too!
Dr. Uranari, tonight is the night—I have made up my mind.
Tomorrow, I will make an announcement that will shock everyone.
Doctor, look forward to tomorrow.
But Your Majesty, that... what on earth is this?
It's a secret.
So, Doctor, please leave me alone.
Well then...
"As of today, I am changing the law of Silverland"
"that forbids women from taking the throne."
"In the name of the King, I hereby decree"
"that a woman may become Queen and rule this land."
There we go.
Patched Gourd
Ah, perfect.
Starting with this, I will change all the bad laws one after another.
I can't take much more of this...
What are you doing?
What are you saying?
Your Highness!
This is terrible!
The King is missing!
What?!
He hasn't been seen anywhere since this morning.
Where is Mother?
Where is everyone?
They're frantically searching everywhere.
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty! Your Majesty!
Search every nook and cranny again—once, twice, three times!
Thoroughly, search thoroughly!
Your Majesty!
Father!
Your Highness!
We searched the castle from top to bottom, but he's nowhere to be found.
Check inside the moat, too!
Right away!
My Queen, the King was up writing something alone all night.
Oh, if something happened to him...
I'll go search again!
The family must be so worried.
Still, for the King to just vanish is truly bizarre.
Keep your mouth shut!
We shall search as well.
Command us as you will.
Father!
Where are you?!
He's not in here, either.
Ah, the armor!
Father!
Even in the ancestral tombs... but...
I heard something!
Father!
Was it just my imagination?
My Prince, someone spotted a figure resembling the King early this morning.
Where?
Over by the northern valley.
Alright, I'll go check!
Opal, head to the northern valley!
Father!
Opal.
What's wrong?
What is it?
It looks like Father's shoe.
Opal, hold the end of this rope in your mouth.
I'm going down.
What's wrong?
OPAL!
It's Father's shoe!
Oh, my darling!
My deepest condolences.
Mother!
Father?!
What happened?
Your Grace,
one week after the King's passing, the Prince will succeed to the throne.
Prince Sapphire's coronation, is it?
If our scheme goes smoothly by then...
it should be quite an interesting coronation!
You fool, Nylon!
Sapphire, it's me.
Come in, Mother.
Mother.
How do I look?
You look beautiful, Sapphire.
You thought I was crying, didn't you?
Yes, I came to comfort you.
I'm not going to cry anymore.
Instead of crying, I decided to dress up.
But why?
It's the last time I'll ever get to dress up.
Once I become King, I'll never be able to wear clothes like this again.
So you decided to wear them one last time.
That's right.
Nanny, were you there?
Yes, I was helping her get dressed.
Don't cry.
Come on, smile.
How could I not cry?
Sapphire, this will certainly not be the last time you dress up.
Once you ascend to the throne, you can change those old laws right away.
So that anyone can become King.
Take a new step so a woman can become queen.
That's true.
Mother, that's what I'll do!
I'll definitely do it.
I won't back down!
♪ Dai kanki ♪
Great joy!
♪ Ureshi ureshi dai kanki ♪
I'm so happy! I'm overjoyed!
♪ Lu lu lu, lu lu lu ♪
-
♪ Ureshi dai kanki ♪
Oh, happy, great joy!
♪ O shiro pikapikapi ♪
The castle is sparkling bright!
♪ Pikapika ♪
Sparkling bright!
♪ Dai kanki ♪
Great joy!
♪ Ureshi ureshi dai kanki ♪
I'm so happy! I'm overjoyed!
♪ Lu lu lu, lu lu lu, lu lu lu ♪
-
♪ Kireina dai kanki ♪
Beautiful, great joy!
♪ Dare mo tsuya tsuya tsuya tsuya ♪
Everyone is glowing and bright!
♪ Tsuya tsuya dai kanki ♪
Glowing, great joy!
♪ Dai kanki ♪
Great joy!
♪ La la, la la, la la la ♪
-
♪ Docchi so mo docchi so mo onaka ga pekopeko ♪
One and all, our tummies are rumbling!
♪ Okashi mo pakupaku pakupaku pakupaku ♪
Munching away on treats!
♪ Oishi gochiso ♪
A delicious feast!
♪ La la lan, la la la la ♪
-
♪ Dai kanki ♪
Great joy!
♪ Kazaro kazaro omatsuri omatsuri ♪
Decorate, decorate for the grand festival!
♪ La la, lan lan, lu lu lu ♪
-
♪ Kazaro kazaro ♪
Decorate, decorate!
♪ La la, la la, la la la ♪
-
♪ Besu wa fu fu ♪
The bass goes puff-puff!
♪ Fu fu fu fu fu fu ♪
puff puff puff puff puff puff!
♪ Rappa wa fu fu ♪
The horn goes puff-puff!
♪ La la la, la la la la ♪
-
♪ La la, la la la la ♪
♪ La la la lo ♪
-
♪ Dai kanki ♪
Great joy!
♪ Okyaku ya okyaku no dai kanki ♪
Welcome, guests! Such great joy!
♪ Lu lu lu, lu lu lu ♪
-
♪ O uma wa pa pa pa pa kuruma mo pon pon pon pon ♪
Horses clip-clopping, carriages chugging along!
♪ Yokoso yokoso ureshi ureshi dai kanki ♪
Welcome, welcome! We're so happy, what great joy!
The Great Jubilee is finally tomorrow.
Preparations at the castle are nearly complete,
and delegates from around the world are arriving one after another.
Ahead of this major ceremony, Prince Sapphire
is surely resting calmly, awaiting the dawn.
Dear God, please grant me courage and strength.
I'm scared.
I'm so terrified of living a lie.
Dawn is already here.
Dear God, please protect me.
Apothecary Ponko, is that poison ready yet?
Hehehehehe, it's almost done.
Just three more hours.
Hurry up, work faster!
We won't make it in time for the Jubilee!
It'll be ready, it'll be ready! Plenty of time before the ceremony.
How effective is it?
One sip and they'll blab whatever's on their mind. It's plenty potent.
If it isn't ready in time, I'll chop off your head!
I'll wait right here until it's finished.
Hurry up and make it.
Move it!
So violent.
I'm thirsty. Got any booze?
On the shelf.
This is it.
Ponko, what kind of booze is this?
You grabbed the wrong one, Mr. Nylon.
That's not booze.
That's a weight-gain potion.
A weight-gain potion?!
Do something! Give me a cure!
There's no quick cure for that.
You'll stay like that until it wears off.
Anything will do! A weight-loss potion!
Here.
What is it, Ponko?
Don't you worry.
You'll be back to normal by the time the potion is ready.
Until then, why don't you take a nice little nap?
We will now begin Prince Sapphire's grand coronation!
I hope everything goes smoothly...
The grand coronation ceremony is about to begin.
Representatives from around the world, dressed in fine attire,
eagerly await the Prince's arrival with bated breath.
Once Prince Sapphire takes this throne, Silverland will welcome its new king.
Grand Duke Duralumin!
Daddy, I want something to eat.
Shh! Be patient, there will be a feast later.
You fool, stop that!
Here, I'll give you some candy.
Presenting Her Majesty the Queen!
Sapphire, I pray the ceremony goes smoothly.
Where on earth is Nylon?
He hasn't shown up at the hall yet.
What is he doing?
Presenting His Highness Prince Sapphire and His Grace the Archbishop!
Accompanied by the choir, the Prince finally makes his entrance!
Next, we shall proceed with the crowning ceremony.
Look, it has over a hundred diamonds on it!
You fool, it has at least two hundred!
Your Grace, Nylon has returned.
She's back!
I'll make it!
Tell him to hurry up and mix the drug into the wine!
The Grand Duke ordered us to mix the potion into the Queen's wine right away.
Give me the medicine!
What?
No!
Why not?!
I'm the one who got the medicine!
I should put it in the Queen's glass myself!
Enough already!
You go rest!
I'll do it!
I said I'll do it!
Get lost!
Just go take a rest!
I won't!
Now then, we shall proceed to the toast.
Everyone, I will now pour the celebratory wine.
Once poured, please do not drink until instructed.
Grand Duke Duralumin, please lead the toast.
Hold on. Is that glass for the Queen?
That's right.
Sounds good. Alright.
Now it's as good as ours!
Now, a toast to King Sapphire and Silverland.
Cheers!
Grand Duke Duralumin!
Wait!
Cheers!
Ah!
Mother!
Someone, take Mother to her room!
It's all right now, it's all right.
I never knew keeping this secret alone would be so painful.
Mother!
Now is the time to reveal everything.
What do you mean?
Sapphire... my child Sapphire is actually a girl.
What?
Yes.
Sapphire is a girl.
To put her on the throne, they forced her to pose as a boy!
Did you all hear that?!
Everyone, that is a direct confession!
For 13 years, this mother and child lied and deceived the nation!
They're traitors!
Cowards who deceived the people!
U-Um... did I say something wrong?
Mother, it's too late!
What?
That's right, it's too late!
You've confessed to everything!
Guards!
Arrest these traitors!
And seize those three henchmen of theirs, too!
This is punishment for deceiving the people!
Prince Sapphire and the Queen shall be locked in the Coffin Tower for life!
Surely no one objects!
The Coffin Tower?
For life?
As for those three, for aiding traitors, they'll be slaves in the quarry!
Slaves in the quarry?!
And on the new throne, my son Plastic shall sit!
No one objects to King Plastic, I presume!
Drag the criminals away!
Now then, Prince Sapphire—or rather, Princess Sapphire—
and Her Majesty, I am afraid you must step into the prison carriage.
Mother, let's go.
Sapphire, forgive me.
Mother we fell right into Duralumin's trap!
He must've been made to drink poisoned wine.
We won't be seeing each other again.
Farewell, then.
That over there is the Coffin Tower.
I pity you, Princess Sapphire, but once you go in there, you'll never leave until you're nothing but bones.
Prepare yourself!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen ♪
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
♪ Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen ♪
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
♪ Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo ♪
Even if demons come, even if storms arrive,
♪ tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai ♪
Our bonded hearts will never part.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP